Guide to the Allen Ginsberg papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Allen Ginsberg papers,
1943-1991
[Bulk Dates: 1945-1976]
Ginsberg, Allen, 1926-1997.
11.25 linear ft. (26 boxes & 1 oversized document box)
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library New York, NY. 10027
MS#0487
4078809
Papers of Allen Ginsberg, American poet and one of the founders of the beat generation. The collection contains correspondence, manuscripts, and publications created by Ginsberg and his associates.
Biographical Note
Allen Ginsberg, born Irwin Allen Ginsberg, grew up in Paterson New Jersey with his parents, Louis and Naomi Ginsberg and his brother Eugene Brooks. Both of Allen's parents were to be major influences on him and his work-- his father, a poet and high school English teacher, was one of his earliest and most constant readers and critics. His mother's mental illness would profoundly affect Ginsberg as well, though in a very different way, ultimately inspiring Ginsberg's poem "Kaddish: for Naomi Ginsberg 1894-1956."
Ginsberg left Paterson for New York City when he was accepted to Columbia University as an undergraduate. He entered University in the Fall of 1943 and soon met fellow Columbia student, Lucien Carr who would introduce Ginsberg to Jack Kerouac and William S. Burroughs. This group of friends would form the nucleus of the Beat Generation. Though a brilliant student, Ginsberg was expelled from Columbia in 1945 for scrawling an obscenity on his window and for engaging in homosexual sex. He did, however, return to the University the next year and completed his BA in 1948.
After Ginsberg's graduation he remained in New York City and his apartment became a meeting place and crash pad for his group of friends, including Herbert Huncke-- a drug addict, petty thief, and Times Square habitue. When the apartment was busted containing Huncke's stolen goods, Huncke took the jail time, but Ginsberg was still implicated. Rather than go to jail, Ginsberg plead that he was psychologically unfit to stand trial and was sent to the Columbia Psychiatric Institute for an eight month sentence. It was here that he met Carl Solomon, to whom he would dedicate the poem "Howl."
After he was released from the psychiatric hospital, Ginsberg remained in New York for a few years, starting to write and working odd jobs, before he moved to San Francisco in 1953. Once he was in San Francisco, he met a group of California artists and poets including Philip Whalen, Michael McClure, Philip Lamantia, and Lawrence Ferlinghetti and became involved in the San Francisco Renaissance movement that was taking place on the west coast literary scene. It was in San Francisco that Ginsberg first wrote "Howl" and read it for the first time at the 1955 Six Gallery reading hosted by Kenneth Rexroth. It was also in San Francisco that Ginsberg met Peter Orlovsky who would be his lover, collaborator, and companion throughout the rest of his life.
Ginsberg spent the next few years nominally based in New York City, but traveling widely. He visited William Burroughs in Tangier, Morocco and famously lived in Paris at "The Beat Hotel" at 9 Rue Git-le-coeur with Gregory Corso and Willaim Burroughs where he helped assemble Burroughs's The Naked Lunch manuscript. He and Peter Orlovsky spent the greater part of 1962-1963 in India. This experience would be the basis for his non-fiction book Indian Journals. He moved back to New York, living in both the city and a farm house in Cherry Valley in upstate New York where he based his non-profit artists' relief fund, The Committee on Poetry.
In 1974 Ginsberg helped to found the Jack Kerouac School of Disembodied Poetics of the Naropa Institute where he was also a member of the faculty. He returned to teach at his alma mater as a visiting professor in 1968 and took a teaching position at Brooklyn College which he retained until his death of liver cancer in 1997.
Scope and Content
The Allen Ginsberg papers contain correspondence, artwork, manuscripts, and printed material by and about Ginsberg, including the manuscript for "Indian Journals" and the manuscript for a collection of Ginsberg's lectures entitled "Allen Verbatim." The collection also contains a significant number of artworks and manuscripts by Ginsberg's friends and associates, including William Burroughs's "Interzone" (Naked Lunch) manuscript. There are a very small number of audio recordings included in the collection as well- a recording of an interview with Ginsberg a reel to reel tape of Ginsberg singing poems of William Blake.
1987 Addition: Letters from Allen Ginsberg to Imamu Amiri Baraka.
1991 Addition: Two tape recordings on the subject of William Blake.
1993 Addition: Books & periodicals.
1998 Addition: Letters from Allen Ginsberg to Arthur Knight.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in 5 series:
Series I: Correspondence, 1943-1982
Series II: Writings and Manuscripts, 1950-1974
Series III: Artwork and Photographs, 1961-1968 and Undated
Series IV: Sound Recordings and Recording Projects, 1967-1971
Series V: Printed Material, 1956-1991
Subjects
Barzun, Jacques, 1907-; Bowles, Paul, 1910-1999.; Burroughs, William S., 1914-1997.; Cassady, Carolyn.; Cassady, Neal.; Charters, Ann.; Corso, Gregory.; Di Prima, Diane.; Ferlinghetti, Lawrence.; Ginsberg, Allen, 1926-1997.; Ginsberg, Louis, 1895-1976.; Kerouac, Jack, 1922-1969.; McClure, Michael.; Miles, Barry, 1943-; Orlovsky, Peter, 1933-; Trilling, Lionel, 1905-1975.; Van Doren, Mark, 1894-1972.; Ball, Gordon.; India--Description and travel.; American literature--20th century.; Beat generation.; Bohemianism--United States.; Literature publishing.; Audio tapes.; Drawings.; Galley proofs.; Journals.; Manuscripts (literary).; Photographs.; Poems.; Videocassettes.; Authors.; Poets.
Access Restrictions
This collection has no restrictions.
This collection is located on-site.
Acquisition
1976 M-76 Purchase
01/08/1992 M-01-08-92 2 tape recordings Boyjiam, Aram Gift
10/--/1993 M-10-93 Printed materials Ginsberg, Allen Gift
05/26/1998 M-98-05-26 AG letters to A. Knight & replies 2293B & 6537B(Bancroft) Purchase
Alternate Formats
W.H. Auden, William Carlos Williams, and William Burroughs letters are on microfilm.
Gift of the Paterson NJ Public Library, 1974.
Gift of Stanley Wertheim, 1986.
Gift of Aram Boyajian, 1992.
Gift of Allen Ginsberg, 1993.
Selected Related Material-- at Columbia
Barry Miles Papers, Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Columbia University.
Peter Orlovsky Papers, Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Columbia University.
William S. Burroughs Papers, Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Columbia University.
Gregory Corso Papers, Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Columbia University.
Selected Related Material-- Other Repositories
Allen Ginsberg Papers, Harry Ransom Humanities Research Center, University of Texas.
Allen Ginsberg Papers, Department of Special Collections Green Library Stanford University Libraries.
- Series I: Correspondence, 1943-1982
  This series consists of correspondence between Allen Ginsberg and his friends, family and associated. Included is early correspondence between Ginsberg and his friends and fellow writers William Burroughs, Jack Kerouac, Neal Cassady, and Gregory Corso as well as letters including poetry critiques from his Columbia University professors Lionel Trilling and Mark Van Doren. There is also a significant amount of correspondence between Allen Ginsberg and his father, the poet Louis Ginsberg.
  - Anderson, John Cutler to Ginsberg, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Auden, W.H. to Ginsberg, 1948 April and 1952 October (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bakken, Richard to Louis Ginsberg, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Barzun, Jacques to Ginsberg
    - 1946 October- 1948 October (3 letters) (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 1959-1965 (7 letters) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Beach, Mary to Ginsberg, 1974 April 2 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Beckett, Samuel to Ginsberg, 1957 October 22 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Behan, Brendan to Ginsberg, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Beltrametti, Franco; Jack Hirschman; Allen Ginsberg; Gary Snyder; and Peter Orlovsky to Claude Pelieu, 1974 June 29 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Blackburn, Paul to Ginsberg, 1961 August and 1966 June-October (4 letters) (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Bowles, Paul to Ginsberg, 1961-1962 and undated (9 letters) (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Brooks, Eugene to Ginsberg
    - 1945-1959 (7 letters, with enclosures) (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - 1961-1963 (10 letters) (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - 1964-1969 (12 letters) (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Burroughs, Joan Vollmer to Ginsberg
    - 1946 November- 1947 March (3 letters) (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - 1949 April- October (2 letters) (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Burroughs, William Seward to Ginsberg
    - Undated (4 letters) (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - 1945 July- 1947 July (8 letters) (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - 1948 (7 letters) (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - 1949 (12 letters) (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - 1950 May-1951 (11 letters) (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - 1952 January- June (17 letters) (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - 1952 July-December (13 letters) (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - 1953 January-May (13 letters) (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - 1953 June-August, 1954 May (12 letters) (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - 1957 September-December (12 letters) (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - 1958 (12 letters) (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - 1959 (18 letters) (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - 1960 (13 letters) (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - 1961 (8 letters) (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - 1962 February-1964 December (9 letters) (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - 1965 December-1969 September (6 letters) (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Carroll, Paul to Ginsberg, 1967 March 20 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    (contains a 39 page essay written by Carroll about Ginsberg's "Wichita Vortex Sutra")
  - Cassady, Carolyn to Ginsberg, 1952-1968 (11 letters) (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Cassady, Neal
    - to Carolyn Cassady, 1958-1959 January (3 letters) (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - to Ginsberg
      - Undated (3 letters) (Box 2, Folder 13)
      - 1947 (15 letters) (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - 1948 (4 letters) (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - 1949-1952 (8 letters) (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - 1953-1954 (5 letters) (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - 1959 (4 letters) (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - 1967 (2 letters) (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - to Jack Kerouac
      - Undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - 1947 October and 1950 December (2 letters) (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - to his Parents and Hal Chase, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence and Documents (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Charters, Ann to Ginsberg, 1970 August 23 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Ciardi, John (Saturday Review) to Ginsberg, 1959 August (2 letters) (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Clemens, Cyril to Ginsberg, 1966 April 27 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Corso, Gregory
    - to Ray Bremser, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - to Ann Campbell, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - to Ginsberg
      - Undated (5 letters) (Box 3, Folder 16)
      - 1956 August-December (5 letters) (Box 3, Folder 17)
      - 1957 (12 letters) (Box 3, Folder 18)
      - [1958] (8 letters) (Box 3, Folder 19)
      - 1958 January-March (12 letters) (2 to Ginsberg and Orlovsky, 3 to Ginsberg and Burroughs) (Box 3, Folder 20)
      - 1958 July-September (8 letters) (Box 3, Folder 21)
      - 1958 October-December (11 letters) (Box 3, Folder 22)
      - 1959 May-July (12 letters) (Box 3, Folder 23)
      - 1959 August -December (15 letters) (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - 1959 May 15 (Box 4, Folder 2)
        (includes notes from Corso to Orlovsky and Kerouac to Ginsberg)
      - 1960 (15 letters) (Box 4, Folder 3)
      - 1961 January-March (8 letters) (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - 1961 September-November (10 letters) (Box 4, Folder 5)
      - 1962 January-July (8 letters) (Box 4, Folder 6)
      - 1962 August-November (10 letters) (Box 4, Folder 7)
      - 1963 (6 letters) (Box 4, Folder 8)
      - 1965-1967 (14 letters) (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - to Louis Ginsberg, undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - to Jack Kerouac, 1961 January 4 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - to Archibald MacLeish, undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - to Peter Orlovsky
      - 1957 (2 letters) (Box 4, Folder 13)
      - [1958] (2 letters) (Box 4, Folder 14)
      - 1958 September-October (2 letters) (Box 4, Folder 15)
      - 1960 (5 letters) (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Corso, Gregory and William Burroughs to Ginsberg and Peter Orlovsky, 1958 September 24 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Cowley, Malcolm to Ginsberg, 1953 July-December (3 letters) (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Creeley, Robert to Ginsberg
    - 1956 September-1958 December (7 letters) (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - 1959-1960 (8 letters) (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - 1962-1963 (11 letters) (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - 1964-1965 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - 1966-1967 (9 letters) (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Crosby, Caresse to Ginsberg, 1957 (3 letters) (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - cummings, e.e., 1956 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Day, Dorothy to Ginsberg, 1961 and 1966 (4 letters) (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - DiPrima, Diane to Ginsberg, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Duncan, Robert to Ginsberg, 1956-1966 (5 letters) (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Eberhart, Richard to Ginsberg, 1956-1966 (5 letters) (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Engle, Paul Hamilton to Ginsberg, 1964-1956 (6 letters) (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Farrell, Lawrence to Gregory Corso, 1958-1961 (3 letters) (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Ferlinghetti, Lawrence
    - to Gregory Corso, 1958-1961 (3 letters) (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - to Max Gartenberg, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - to Ginsberg
      - 1957 (5 letters) (Box 5, Folder 15)
      - 1958 (15 letters) (Box 5, Folder 15)
      - 1959 (10 letters) (Box 5, Folder 16)
      - 1960 (15 letters) (Box 5, Folder 17)
      - 1961 (23 letters) (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Ferlinghetti, Lawrence
    - to Ginsberg
      - 1962 (22 letters) (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - 1963 (11 letters) (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - 1964 (20 letters) (Box 6, Folder 3)
      - 1965 (8 letters) (Box 6, Folder 4)
      - 1966 (16 letters) (Box 6, Folder 5)
      - 1967 (9 letters) (Box 6, Folder 6)
      - 1968 (7 letters) (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - to Peter Orlovsky, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - to Claude Pélieu and Mary Beach, 1973 July- 1974 October (7 letters) (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Ford, Charles Henri to Ginsberg
    - 1952 (3 letters) (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - 1964-1968 (10 letters) (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Gallup, Donald to Ginsberg, 1964-1965 (3 letters) (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Garver, William Maynard to Ginsberg, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Geffen, Felicia (National Institute of Arts and Letters) to Ginsberg, 1957 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Ginsberg, Allen
    - to unknown recipient, undated (Box 6, Folder 16)
      (possibly discussing the work of Anselm Hollo)
    - to Gordon Ball, 1973-1974, (2 Folders) (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - to Amiri and Amina Baraka, 1978 March and 1980 November (2 letters) (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - to Amiri Baraka, 1978 and 1981 (3 letters) (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - to Bill Berkson, 1968-1969 (3 letters) (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - to Eugene Brooks
      - 1943-1945 (4 letter) (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - 1956-1957 (10 letters) (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - to Ann Buchanan, 1972 (2 letters) (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - to William Burroughs
      - 1949-1952 and undated (4 letters) (Box 7, Folder 5)
      - 1960 July (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - to Bill Butler, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - to Neal Cassady, undated (3 letters) (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - to Gregory Corso, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 9)
      (contains transcript of a discussion following a poetry reading)
    - to Mr. Creagh, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - to Marcel Duchamp, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - to Gail Dusenbery, 1970 (5 letters) (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - to Edith Ginsberg, 157 December 15 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - to Louis Ginsberg
      - 1947-1948 and undated (5 letters) (Box 7, Folder 14)
      - 1954, 1956-1957 (15 letters) (Box 7, Folder 15)
      - 1958-1959 (9 letters) (Box 7, Folder 16)
      - 1960-1961 (16 letters) (Box 7, Folder 17)
      - 1962-1963 (16 letters) (Box 7, Folder 18)
      - 1965 (12 letters) (Box 7, Folder 19)
      - 1967 September-1969 August (7 letters) (Box 7, Folder 20)
      - 1970s and undated (3 letters) (Box 7, Folder 21)
      - 1970 (17 letters) (Box 8, Folder 1)
      - 1971 (14 letters) (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - 1972 (21 letters) (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - 1973 (25 letters) (Box 8, Folder 4)
      - 1974 (19 letters) (Box 8, Folder 5)
      - 1975-1976 (8 letters) (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - to Dave Haselwood
      - 1967 and undated (9 letters) (Box 8, Folder 7)
      - 1968-1969 (5 letters) (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - to Pietro Heliczer, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - to Jeremy Hilton, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - to Herbert Huncke (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - to Jack Kerouac, undated, 1945-1949 (4 letters) (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - to Jack Kerouac and William Burroughs, 1951-1952 (2 letters) (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - to Arthur and Glee Knight, 1970-1975 (11 letters) (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - to Arthur and Kit Knight, 1976, 1984 (3 letters) (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - to Paolo Lionni, 1956 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - to Kenneth Lohf, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - to Tom McGrath, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - to Kirsten Michalski, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - to Claude Pélieu and Mary Beach, 1968 and 1973 December- 1974 July (10 letters) (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - to [Robert] Gene [Pippin], 1950 (Box 9, Folder 8)
      (contains poem "If Money Made the Mind More Sane")
    - to Janine Pommey, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - to Jonathan Robbins, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - to Miss Rosenberg, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - to Barney Rossett, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - to Lionel Trilling, 1945-1950 (3 letters) (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - to Mark Van Doren, undated (2 letters) (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - to A.A. Wyn, 1953 (Box 9, Folder 15)
      (regarding distribution of Junkie)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1966-1982 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    (unaddressed, etc.)
  - Ginsberg, Jack Kerouac, Peter Orlovsky and Gregory Corso to "Jim" [James Weschler], undated (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Ginsberg and William Burroughs to Tom Briberg, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Ginsberg, Louis
    - to City Lights Publishing, 1960 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - to Gail Dusenberg, 1968 (6 letters) (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - to Eugene and Connie Brooks, 1957 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - to Allen Ginsberg
      - Undated (Box 9, Folder 22)
      - 1945-1948 (12 letters) (Box 9, Folder 23)
      - 1955 December (2 letters) (Box 9, Folder 24)
      - 1956 (16 letters) (Box 9, Folder 25)
      - 1957-1958 (13 letters) (Box 9, Folder 26)
      - 1959-1960 (18 letters) (Box 9, Folder 27)
      - 1961 (22 letters) (Box 9, Folder 28)
      - 1962 (22 letters) (Box 10, Folder 1)
      - 1963 (23 letters) (Box 10, Folder 2)
      - 1964 (10 letters) (Box 10, Folder 3)
      - 1965 (22 letters) (Box 10, Folder 4)
      - 1966 January-July (23 letters) (Box 10, Folder 5)
      - 1966 August-December (21 letters) (Box 10, Folder 6)
      - 1967 (37 letters) (Box 10, Folder 7)
      - 1968 (18 letters) (Box 10, Folder 8)
      - 1969, (6 Folders) (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - to Selden Rodman, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Ginsberg, Naomi Levy
    - to Eugene Brooks and Louis Ginsberg, 1948 and 1950s (4 letters) (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - To Ginsberg, 1948, 1956 and undated (17 letters) (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Ginsberg, Rebecca to Ginsberg, undated (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Holmes, John Clellon to Ginsberg, 1949-1964 (7 letters) (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Huxley, Aldous to Ginsberg, 1961 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Huxley, Laural to Ginsberg, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Kent, Rockwell to Ginsberg, 1964 February 14 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Kerouac, Edie Parker to Ginsberg, 1945 January 17 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Kerouac, Gabrielle-Ange Levesque
    - to Jack Kerouac, 1949 February 1 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - to Ginsberg, 1958 and 1959 (2 letters) (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Kerouac, Jack
    - Unaddressed and undated (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - to Alan Ansen, 1957 August 20 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - to William S. Burroughs, 1947 ang 1955 (2 letters) (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - to Carolyn Robinson Cassady, 1954 May 17 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - to Neal Cassady, undated (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - to Max and Eleanor Frohman, circa 1952 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - to Ginsberg
      - Undated (5 letters) (Box 11, Folder 13)
      - 1944-1945 (11 letters) (Box 11, Folder 14)
      - 1947-1948, (11 Folders) (Box 11, Folder 15)
        (one letter includes a letter from Lucien Carr)
      - 1949 (7 letters) (Box 11, Folder 16)
      - 1950 (7 letters) (Box 11, Folder 17)
      - 1951 (4 letters) (Box 11, Folder 18)
      - 1952 (14 letters) (Box 11, Folder 19)
      - 1953 (7 letters) (Box 11, Folder 20)
      - 1954 (11 letters) (Box 11, Folder 21)
        (includes copies of poems later included in San Francisco Blues
      - 1955 (18 letters) (Box 12, Folder 1)
      - 1956-1957 (14 letters) (Box 12, Folder 2)
      - 1958 (15 letters) (Box 12, Folder 3)
      - 1959 March-June (10 letters) (Box 12, Folder 4)
      - 1959 July-December (12 letters) (Box 12, Folder 5)
      - 1960 (9 letters) (Box 12, Folder 6)
      - 1961 (8 letters) (Box 12, Folder 7)
      - 1962 April-November, 1963 June 97 letters) (Box 12, Folder 8)
      - 1966, 1968 (2 letters) (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - to John Clellon Holmes, undated (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - to James Laughlin, 1951-1952 (2 letters) (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - to Peter Orlovsky
      - 1956 and undated (3 letters) (Box 12, Folder 12)
      - 1959 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - to Carl Solomon, 1951 December- 1952 April (2 letters) (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Krassner, Paul to Ginsberg, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    (written on copy of The Realist)
  - LaVigne, Robert to Barry Miles, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Lea, George to Lawrence Ferlinghetti, 1960 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    (includes Lea's review of "Kaddish")
  - Lowell, Robert to Ginsberg, 1959 April (2 letters) (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Lowenfels, Walter to Ginsberg, undated, 1958-1968, (14 letters) (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - McClure, Jo Ann Keera to Ginsberg and Peter Orlovsky, 1964 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - McClure, Michael
    - to Gregory Corso, 1961 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - to Ginsberg
      - undated, 1956-1957 (10 letters) (Box 13, Folder 8)
      - 1958-1959 (19 letters) (Box 13, Folder 9)
      - 1960-1961 (11 letters) (Box 13, Folder 10)
      - 1963-1964 (9 letters) (Box 13, Folder 11)
      - 1965 (6 letters) (Box 13, Folder 12)
      - 1966 1967 June (14 letters) (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - McInnerney, Michael to Barry Miles, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Micheline, Jack to Ginsberg, 1960 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Miles, Barry to Ginsberg, 1965, 1970 (2 letters) (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Miles, Josephine to Ginsberg, 1957 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Moore, Marianne to Ginsberg, 1952 June-July and 1957 January (4 letters) (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - National Union of South African Students to Ginsberg, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    (with enclosures)
  - O'Hara, Frank to Ginsberg, 1958-1961 (4 letters) (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Olsen, Charles to Ginsberg, 1957-1966 (10 letters) (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Ono, Yoko to Jonas Mekas, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Orlovsky, Peter
    - to Amiri and Amina Baraka, 1978 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - to Barry Miles, 1971, 1973 (2 letters) (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Pelieu, Claude to Ginsberg, 1974 (2 letters) (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Pound, Dorothy to Ginsberg, 1952 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Ransom, John Crowe to Ginsberg, undated (2 letters) (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Read, Sir Herbert to Ginsberg, 1958 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Rodman, Selden to Ginsberg, 1960-1961, 1964 (5 letters) (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Rudge, Olga to Ginsberg, 1967 September-October (3 letters) (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Russell, Bertrand to Ginsberg, 1962 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Salisbury, Harrison Evans to Ginsberg, 1968 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Solomon, Carl to Jack Kerouac, 1951-1952 (3 letters) (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Spender, Stephen to Ginsberg, undated (Box 14, Folder 14)